She wasn't a divorcee but she believed that strangers could kiss!
A Free Soul is a drama, romance film directed by Clarence Brown.
An alcoholic lawyer who successfully defended a notorious gambler on a murder charge
objects when his free-spirited daughter becomes romantically involved with him.
Jan Ashe, played by Norma Shearer.
Dwight Winthrop, played by Leslie Howard.
Stephen Ashe, played by Lionel Barrymore.
Ace Wilfong, played by Clark Gable.
Eddie, played by James Gleason.
Grandma Ashe, played by Lucy Beaumont.
A Free Soul is a 1931 American pre-Code drama film directed by Clarence Brown, starring Norma
Shearer, and featuring Leslie Howard, Lionel Barrymore, James Gleason, and Clark Gable.
The film became famous for Barrymore's climactic courtroom monologue, and he
won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his performance.
Gable made such an impression in the role of a gangster who bullies Shearer
that he was catapulted from supporting player to leading man.
The film explores themes of gangster, murder, alcoholic, pre-code.
The tone is emotional.